Rodrigo Leles

Senior Product Designer

rodrigoleles.com dribbble.com/rodrigoleles

São Paulo, Brazil contato@rodrigoleles.com +55 11 996 209 728

I have been building digital products and brands with a focus on crafting exceptional user experiences for over 15 years. Currently working as a freelancer with various agencies, startups, companies and people all over the world.

Professional Experience

Senior Product Designer at IFTTT • Mar 2021 - Jul 2024

IFTTT is a leading internet connectivity platform providing connectivity solutions to the world's most innovative brands, helping 22 million people discover and create useful agents. Some highlights of our design work:

- Kicked-off Al initiatives enabling users to leverage LLMs when creating automations.
- Led a full revamp of the product's design system, reducing design-to-development time by 33% and dropping the number of tickets related to UI bugs by 50%.
- Drove a 10% increase in website call-to-action engagement, positively impacting MRR.

Head of Design at Cooklist • Aug 2018 - Mar 2020

Cooklist has an amazing mission: Make people eat intelligently. My role was not only define the UX vision and strategy but create the end-to-end customer experience and UI at both the macro and micro interaction level:

- Implemented a user research routine, actively talking to real users to gather data about our assumptions to identify and measure critical product KPIs.
- Boosted user retention and improved App Store rating to 4.8, with over 9,000 reviews.
- Contributed to the app's winning entry in the 2018 Techstars Accelerator program.

UX Lead at 99 (Didi Chuxing) • Sep 2017 - Aug 2018

99 is the largest Brazilian ride hailing service, one of the largest startup in Latin America and the first Brazilian unicorn. My role was to support the safety squad with UX design and strategy:

- Ideated, tested and delivered 50+ safety focused features for before, during and after the ride experience for drivers and passengers.
- Led a safety for women program, engaging coworkers to learn about empathy and how a simple digital feature can impact qualitative metrics.

UX Designer at Anheuser-Busch InBev • Jul 2015 - Aug 2017

As part of Anheuser-Busch InBev Disrupt Growth Office we led a global brand and UI initiative for a handful digital experiments, like the one that inspired Zé Delivery: LATAM's leading beverage delivery app:

- Led UI efforts and established an A/B testing center of excellence for web, leading to a 20% increase in A.O.V. and a 5% reduction bounce rate.
- Managed international design systems across Brazil, Mexico, Argentina, and the Dominican Republic.
- Designed and launched a beer-collecting app MVP that achieved a 4.3-star rating with 1,400+ user reviews and ranked in the Top 10 of the App Store's Food & Drink category in Brazil.

Digital Art Director at Artplan • Oct 2014 - Jul 2015

As the Senior Art Director my role consisted in creating and developing ideas in a multiplatform format for integrated campaigns. Joined projects for clients such as Amil, Amanco, Estácio, Itaipava, Etna, Niely, Melitta, Caixa and Rock in Rio.

Education

Interview Workshop: Get the Most out of Your Interviewees • 2018 Ivan Mizanzuk (online)

Intensive Art Direction • 2017 Escola CUCA

Design, Aesthetics and Art Direction • 2016 Saulo Milleti

Digital Design Bachelor • 2006 - 2010 Anhembi Morumbi University

Certifications

The Webflow Masterclass • 2019 Flux Academy (Teachable)

The 10k Website Process • 2020 Flux Academy (Teachable)

UX Design On Demand • 2016 General Assembly

Lean Six Sigma White Belt • 2016 Anheuser-Busch InBev